Next time you see a pigeon flying around, look at it with some respect - it might be able to help with the diagnosis and treatment of human diseases.
下次当你看到一只鸽子四处飞翔时，要带着几分敬意看待它——它或许能够帮助对人类疾病进行诊断和治疗。
A recent study has shown that these birds could be trained to detect breast cancer from images as accurately as humans.
最近的一项研究表明，这些鸽子可以经过训练，像人类一样准确地从图像中检测出乳腺癌。
It's all about their visual memory - these birds have plenty of it even if their brains are very small.
这一切都归功于它们的视觉记忆——尽管这些鸽子的大脑非常小，但它们却拥有强大的视觉记忆能力。
Professor Edward Wasserman from the University of Iowa, a co-author of the study, says: "Pigeons can distinguish identities and emotional expressions on human faces, letters of the alphabet, misshapen pharmaceutical capsules, and even paintings by Monet versus Picasso."
爱荷华大学的爱德华·沃瑟曼教授是这项研究的合著者之一，他说：“鸽子能够区分人类面部的个性特征和情感表达、字母表中的字母、形状不规则的药品胶囊，甚至还能区分莫奈和毕加索的画作。”
And Wasserman adds that the birds' visual memory capacity is equally impressive, with a proven recall of more than 1,800 images.
沃瑟曼还补充说，鸽子的视觉记忆能力同样令人印象深刻，经证实它们能够回想起超过1800张图像。
So how did the scientists find out about the amazing ability of these birds?
那么科学家们是如何发现这些鸽子的惊人能力的呢？
They taught different pigeons to distinguish microscope images of cancerous and non-cancerous tissue and rewarded them with food every time they got it right.
他们训练不同的鸽子区分显微镜下癌变的和非癌变的组织图像，并且每次鸽子判断正确时，就给它们食物作为奖励。
It didn't take long to get good results.
没过多久就取得了良好的效果。
After two weeks of training in 'pigeon medical school', the 'students' recorded 85% accuracy as they managed to identify cancerous tissue from images they had not seen before.
在“鸽子医学院”接受了两周的训练后，这些“学生”能够从它们从未见过的图像中识别出癌变组织，准确率达到了85%。
But pigeons are not the only animals showing potential to help human diagnosis.
但鸽子并不是唯一有潜力帮助人类进行诊断的动物。
A team at the University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences has shown that a dog can be trained to smell urine samples of patients to identify thyroid cancer.
阿肯色大学医学科学团队已经证明，狗可以经过训练嗅闻患者的尿液样本，以识别甲状腺癌。
It lay down when it could smell cancer and turned away if not.
当它能嗅出癌症时就会趴下，如果没有检测到癌症则会转身离开。
The animals got it right in 30 cases out of 34.
在34个案例中，这些狗正确判断了30个。
So don't dismiss the abilities of these animals.
所以不要轻视这些动物的能力。
They might be much more intelligent than you think.
它们可能比你想象的要聪明得多。